Tim Papua Uh house of investment and so
on
Okay who is sunli financial he
healthcare so our our company
realignment it our visions or this is
our company vision with the establish
of sunli grepa health care the company
further emphasize the need to focus on
health and wellness we strive to change
our client
perception of group insurance from
papers
to payers to partners so hindi lang
that's not favor That's a payer to
partners from So that's a payer I'm
sorry for the type of graphical error po
so  we do not treat
our clients as a payer
so we treat our clients
as our
partners who we are we are Sun Life
grepa healthcare are a unit under Sun
Life grepa who offer companies and
organizations various health and
protection what we
do So we are with you and your employee
in every step of your wellness
protections recovery Journey to healthy
and brighter life so what we offer what
is offered by Sun Life grea we offer
businesses with a range wide range of
Comprehensive wellness
protections
recovery insurance CB solutions to help
ignite employ productivity of course
when we have health  insurance so
we feel that we are a part of that
company Same also with our clients that
we can fail
right
let's
ay
so
last2 becoming the insurer choice of
micro small Med
enterprises through this campaign
sunny grepa work with all distribution
channel to focus on tapping into the
under insured Market
of micro small medium enterprises TH
simple affordable and
comprehensive ah We also offer packages
and we created rates are pre-approved
so that the distribution can sell
instant without main office intervention
So um it means to say that  we offer this
Smart care product um the
requirements
needed are less how we can help how we can help
use
Sorry how we can help you
That's not cut That's not a cat huh How How
we can cut You So how we can help
you so ah I would like to introduce to
you our Smart care
plus smarter plus is a Secure health and
future for work force what can
we expect with with Smart care
plus comprehensive benefits with with
build a PL that would protect our
employee from live major
uncertainties like Dead
disability accident  and critical
illness number two is affordable premium
So um  We started with a price of
342 It's depends later We will
go to ah deeper so number the
last one is easy and convenient
administration no requirement medical
examination so what is he more ah
He is easier to sell for us as an
agent ah who are our target market so
our target market is the eligible group
employee and
employer groups with 5 to 200 employees
so when you have a top
company with five they can get this
one the smart care plus You can
he will be offered if that particular
company is looking for
protections and then eligible
insured for how many years can he be
for regular
employee full time and actively at work
from 18 years old to 64 years old
terminate age is termination age is 65
years old and then I just want to to to to
tell you that this I just want to remind
you about the important reminders so Uh
on Okay 80% of the company total work
force should be performing non-hazardous
occupation What does this mean  not
too high risk so maybe later It's
a  chemical It's a chemical company and
then 80% of them are chemical what are they
developing chemicals so
they are exposed to the risk of chemicals So that
means That's a big no So we're
going to them mostly to make it
safer for those in
offices at least
80% and then number two
is 100% of the group must be enrolled in
the plan It's not possible for just the
boss's bet h just the
boss's favorite bet or favorite employee of the year
it
100% ma sry let's deep dive on that po
no um when you say
100% of the group must be enrolled in
the plan meaning all of the employees
Whether it's regular or under
provisionary or kapag O basta regular
employees lang um
Yes ah it really depends on the
company some some of our clients ah
they have enrolled
their probationaries But
some regularization upon day one
provisional they enroll life
insurance or something else upon
regularization when we say just clarify
The 100% is because we said that
per classification for example
he has 100 employees but the client only wants
5 years and Above based on tenure
so all 5 years and Above should
still be 100% It is not possible for those who
have qualified only 10 not possible
based on their company policy YES Or but it
must be full 100% or maybe only all
supervisors and up should be that
only and the basis of 100% must be
enrolled is we can see in the Master
list kyc that do you require sss
no no no no no So the Master list is
the basis because of course we work by trust
' is it really G in insurance so
this um this product is
only employer kyc not employee kyc
not okay that's good thank you But
ah if less than 20 We will be later sig
go - Lea discusses We will be requiring
each employee to fill out a health
declaration form There are only 42 and below
But when he is 20 and Above no need
for the health declaration form that's
part of the underwrite
and lastly for non contributory plan what
is non contributory plan this is when the employee can't
cash it's more on
that the pay is the
company
Okay so no share or something like
We won't tell sun Crea
that we are paying So that's
big ah we are going ah we will know We will still know
Just in
case Okay because if you lie that
still has an impact let's say I don't want to
Eh I don't want to pay because I have a share
but I haven't resigned yet or so it will
have an impact on the contract
so it's very important that we are honest when it
comes to contributory and non
contributory and then um when
we don't tell the truth like Just in
case that that Uh there are cases where
the employee um resigned in the
middle of the policy year then suddenly
messaged us no leya Can I
get my Php 3342 because
I paid to company ABCD So
that's what we will know and we will know
if that in case that can Ah can
sandli crepa hold the contract with
Uh with that particular
ah particular account will be subject
for What is
he here? So this is the
product
design
okay we have two product benefit for Sun
for smart gear plus we have the
protection and the health so for the
protections Uh we offer the we call that
Uh group annually renewable term life
number two I know some of you Especially
there among the Agents This is not the first
time you encounter guys these
words so the difference ah
between us with the Uh compare with other
other insurance company Those
executions for that particular writers
or particular
product So um we  have for protection we
have the group annually renewable term
life total and permanent disability
income
benefits number three is family
assistant benefits we call that family
assistant benefits There is a term
because it is called nama mbit we call that
burial benefits because ah You know
when we Filipinos are told that we are
too stupid What is that to us? We are
too much sensitive our world so as with
Uh with sunli grepa we change it into
family assistant benefits so We also
offer terminal illness
benefits accident dead dismemberment and
disablement benefits and  lastly the
accident medical reimbursement  benefits
and for Health we have the critical
illness benefits in three variants so we
have five cover critical illness so that
five later we will stamp from different
slide and We also have 15 cover critical
illness and we have
36 covered critical illness and lastly
we offer the group hospital cash
benefits Excuse me, I have a question
again for
Zoom Fernandez, his question is
you're referring the employees How about
their
dependence for smart care plus we decide
this product is for the employee only
so since  This is a live and protection
employee even if you look at
him with compare with different
different company insurance company once
It's protections or life insurance is
just on direct for the
employee so we can just what Uh we can
creater for dependence for the just what is
he in the
customize Thank you po Thank you so much
for the question is there still
customization is 20 and
Above Hi Ma'am Ma'am is here pretty
naninawa I really remember ma'am the
last time as many questions
not the most  the amount is most prities par prities
nn  ma'am question about the family
assistance benefit ' are you saying it's the
burial Okay ah for corporate accounts do
you release it Uh
immediately even without the death
certificate Yes Mike po or by the way Okay
sorry so usually the question of Ma'am
if ever There Will Be claim na po ' is
ma'am for example na-no we for
example employee a passed away so some
companies because I understand the upon
notification they release the bral
benefit which Sabi nga natin sometimes
It's 10% of the actual coverage of the
su short for example po or minimum
10,000 20,000 just for so the purpose is
for the burial nga but with us po
we sinasama namin siya sa pag-release
ng life insurance hindi namin siya
pero I think pwede naman i-request in
advance but normally po we require kasi
the documents first the complete
documents before we release any proceed
Yes to others because as long as HR said is
n't there Nam Yes there is a loss
the burial benefit is released immediately Yes
Ah okay Ma'am I'll check that But this is
our process now  because that's why I'm
being asked because that's why if there's no
name Yes what's the point of just preparing
for the week when the deceased died
because if he was with the life
insurance what's the point of having a
separate family assistance
benefit Okay Ma'am wel Double check on
that wel text the claims we bet I
understand that's the standard process
we're talking about
because we still need to ask or receive the complete documents claim documents because maybe contestable 'ba may mga
then they will take back
the B they gave me I have time with
their employee ah personally
I experienced that with me
when my mom passed away so the company
who cashed out so I was surprised like
Why did he immediately indicate it
but he also had it depends on the
agreement between the employee and the company
I have a question like an agreement that
when I received it with my insurance
that sort of amount most of the
companies doing it ma'am Okay that's okay
if there is no if it is not included in the
claims can
your employer advance it but what if it is
included So the employer is a subscriber there
Okay Ma we're going to get back on you
ma because thank you so much ma'am
okay for protection benefits what else do
we have
for protections benefit we have the a
basic package for grp really renewable
term life or we call the
gyr gyr provide life insurance
protections Anytime Anywhere or any
cause of death
except suicide on the first year of
coverage so do you have question on that
but we don't encourage that
but we  don't encourage it's nice to
have him but we don't encourage
you Especially to our young
listeners now We don't encourage maybe
later you'll think about it Le said after
one year so after my year because I provide
I can do it So that's a big big no
so he opened and closed parenthesis
number two is for total permanent
disability income or we call that tpd
benefits for tpd benefits
advances from gyr benefits in
the case that employee is diagnosed to
be totally and permanently
disabled so do you have question on
that no one will ask how
regin Velasquez lost his voice
Can he get it Ah can
he get it since regen Velasquez was insured he is
no longer since what he does for a
living is singing he lost his
voice
ah no one will ask me
not okay for Reg vases is different from
as we as we all know that This is smart
care plus so Uh we cater only for those who have an
accident and by cause by accident that's
total and permanent
disability not just because Uh because it's another
type of insurance that's for the
voice only he should be Because maybe later there
those by accident
even
me okay
um so ah for total permanent disability
income Uh issue issue age benefits from
18 to 59 years old and termination age
is 60 in virginity
that's the time pa yung what is he yung
termination nung nyang policy So Ma'am
question po no since this this um
product na to is up to 65 ah 64 years
old ang termination nyang is
65 So ibig siya yung
tpd tpd nyang is up to up to 6 years
old he has 4 years he doesn't have this kind of thing that will be
removed from his benefit yes
Okay what is the reason why he wasn't
made 64 yet um because
ah do you have an answer there about Why do
up to 60 so since the smart k
up to what is the live because up to 65
the tpd because up to 60 B That's all because
the IC approved in our product
even the customized ang tpd ib namin is
up to 60 years old o and take note ha
what is he income benefit for some because there are
no lamps we give monthly
pension for 5 years so it's also A
Difference not him Iyung  ppd lang
benefit it says there Uh it advances so
the the benefit is gotten from the gyr
so it's not
really additional or a different corre a
separate benefit benefit correct so
when so example po ah halimbawa si
employee na-diagnosed na siya as tpd
totally and permanently disabled so for
six months continuous na siya na bed
readin comatos so na na siya na certifi
ng at least two doctors na tpd kasi
meron meron partial and temporary ' ba po
meron din totally and permanently disabled
so Bibigyan po natin siya ng monthly
pension So that's what he's getting from life
insurance
he's not getting it in advance nga
yung life insurance so If in case on the
third year na wala si member yung
remaining Yeah yung remaining
He's just the balance of life insurance but
he's also not getting life coverage so
there's a possibility the gyr benefit
could be exhausted Yes ma'am Opo Upon
The paying period within the 5 years
because for some insurance lamps he's
being given 500,000 500,000 immediately so is it
clear
number three is  the family assistant
benefits or Pub ah Pub is provide an
additional benefits to the
employee family to pay for Uh funeral
and burial related expense this is what
we said
earlier so lastly is the terminal illness
benefits the tib Uh issuance age is 18
to 59 years old
termination date is Age is 60 for the
for tib advance 50% of the gyr benefits
if employee is diagnosed to be terminally
ill terminally ill where life Uh
expectancy less than 12 months So how
where will he get it still there
like for example the gyr is
100,000 so for when the
member is diagnosed with terminal illness 50% from
100,000 the amount that will be given in advance to
him Yes As for the family assistance
benefit How much is it It's depend
on the coverage requested by the client
Like for example 10%
10% Ma'am about the question because of
course we have entered a query so we can get
feedback immediately Isn't it so as for our
claims This is what is it that
our claims department and  at least soft copy of
the debt certificate we can advance the
Pub This is our family assistance
benefit as long as the policy is
more than one year because
we have a one year contestability period fa
will be paid same time with the when
more when within again when
the policy is more than one year because there is
no contestability period
we can advance soft copy of the
certificate when within one year
pa lang kasabalan po siya ng group life Yes
what I'm saying is because the death
certificate sometimes is not obtained immediately
so when HR finds out that this
person has actually died it should be
released usually within 24
hours eh HR pays
so especially if the policy is More Than a year
the release should be faster
because there is no contestability
Yes even without the death certificate to
follow just as long as
HR signs something that he is sure that
this employee is no longer there because the expense was there in the UN in the
early days, right? Yes we understand Yes
we understood Of course the
purpose of the burial benefit is not
burial assistance however That's all it is
This is really it I just read
our Amil sure Ma'am just that it depends
on what it is easy to
discuss especially if
the benefit of the fab is only 10,000 20,000 That's it
Yes ' is that the point That's
okay I also have a question there on
terminal illness So what is
your requirement to declare terminally ill Ah
the doctor diagnostic to be what is it
really concise let's with that particular
document the abstract because the
abstract coming from the doctor is
really written there ah um
really indicates if that ah that
particular patient is has any more
recovery or on the period of time
he specified briefly
a so medical abstract Yes and
then Yes at least two doctors to give
a Yes Okay but they won't even
put that what he has tanning
no Because that's not
[Music]
s-corp because of cancer So do you have specific
what illnesses and what
stage
OP is just what
Mike please it's different because it's different
even if it's cancer stage 4 he
can recover so it's not  we are also
recovering him, so that is the
purpose of the advance payment
of terminal illness benefit for the
patient's recovery. Okay, so just make it clear that
you don't require the doctor to
stay there for less than 12 months.
There is no doctor who says that
you have only been there for 3 months.
It's a bit unethical. Okay,
thank you. Ma'am, I just have a question
because, oh, the contestability period, are
we talking about like, oh, the one who
committed suicide, because earlier,
your contestability period is for suicide
only. Yes, this is what Ma'am is asking about, Ma'am, the one from the accident, the one from the
accident, family
assistance, because what does he have? There is
still a contestability period for
the person who died. Ma'am's only question
is, what are the claims for one year, which is
more than a soft copy,
but because insurance sometimes they don't
know or no one among
all people, we don't know what.
How much time do we have, right?
After getting the insurance approved,
then it goes to the company.  one of their
employees died due to an
accident That's not included because there needs to be a
contestability period. It's not
necessary that it's not included or that
our contestability period is only covered by one year of investigation. That's
right, for example. Yes, it's
just for Sickness. No, for all, okay, for
example, the policy period is January
1, 2025, up to December 31, 2025. So there's one.
So for example, an
employee enrolled 20 employees on
January 1, then added
three employees on February 1. So the
three still need to be one year old.
They won't be included in the one year
policy year, so all 20 of them are already one
year old. Until December,
if the client has renewed the account in
2026, I won't disregard
[Music]
the employee who is gone, we will ask for
additional requirements
regardless of whether he is gone because of an
accident or illness. Because maybe
he already has a medical history or
something, but it's an accident, I guess
that's common in accidents, but what force is
that? The policy is the life insurance
of that employee, we will release
100,000 to continue
the cost of Deb, but if
client C renews in 2026, there will be no
additional requirements asked, so
clients, not the employee. Okay, yes, because
our policy is, I'm a little
scared because I have a client I'm
taking care of right now.  it's the same
ent no claim maybe I'll be the one to fire won't I
explain okay okay because it's acceptable to others
Once it's approved
what the client's policy has been given to us
even if the owner hasn't gotten it yet
'cause when we get it approved it's
paid it's enforced he fell over or
whatever at work or not enforce
the accident the policy is individual is
it non corporate also Okay so
corporate when it's an
accident the normal accident let's say
obviously got run over ' is it covered
That's right but the case like okay
the example I had before with my client
ah they saw in the CR that he was dead so the
question there was was he attacked that's why he
fell or did he fall that he was crazy that
accident wasn't it So or maybe he
committed suicide So the ones in that case
Those with a contestability period of one
year that they will investigate first Yes the
unknown ones Yes maybe just to
simplify I'll just add something when it says
contestability period it's just that there will be an
investigation to be done but it doesn't
mean that yes deny it won't just be
given right away because the case is going to
be investigated there may be further  document or when
it's the second year and there's nothing
to ask, give it immediately, that's the simplest
explanation, so within one
year there's a contest, maybe.
You're just changing the word contestable. So the
only word is within one year,
we'll just ask for additional requirements when something is
lost. Yes, yes, because
within one
year, because I read to you what our claims said, as long as it's within
one year. Yes, that's it. Yes, it's included in everything. Yes, it should be
ah temporarily Ma'am he is still
available So what we have the soft copy
if
you you wish we can
send it because right now Uh
our marketing team is still fixing everything
Yes there are revisions Maybe ma'am You can
just send it to us so
we can upload it to our shared folder
I we understand that This is a new
product for deps Yes okay for for a
triple d Uh pays an additional benefits
in any case or Accidental debt
dismemberment and
disablement here it comes in Like for
example si si member ah na due to
accident ah may mga na naputol na parts
sa katawan niya So we have here the
schedule of emi so number one if si memp
Ah namatay cause nung
accident 100% Iyung life for entire eyes
side or both eyes side um Uh both hands
or both feet one hands one foot either
hands or foot s of one eye 100% that's what
member can get for arms for arm or
above elbow
so above elbow so
he just wants to what ha to clarify maybe
later since You know there is something to
cut off it is  accident not
the one that was really cut off just to
get something ha because I saw Ma'am
smiling eh What she was saying oh my
god I can cut it off later so
I can get 100% no so due to accident
not the one that was intentional so for
legs or above knee
60% one hand at or above ris
50% hearing or both both Yung sa
hearing sight or one eye one four
fingers from TH of the hand so for so
Dapat
ito
Sorry so yon Do you have any questions
about this schedule of emi
Okay ah clear na po po
for um Accidental medical
reimbursement or amr benefits Uh
reimbursement in patient and outpatient
medical expenses in cure to treat bily
due to
accident ang ano
um Depende ah
um
mga ilang ah later Ma'am igakasyon po
namin May ibibigay kaming diagram po mamay
Uh for Health benefits so cib we call
that cib critical illness benefits for
critical illness benefits provide a
fixed cost benefits upon diagnosis of
any of the covered critical illness
subject to the following condition so
mamay I'm going to go deeper about
what are the illnesses that are classified as
critical illness so for a the
critical illness was diagnosed by
registered Doctor and agreed to by Sun
Life grepa medical
officer B the critical illness occur
more than 90 days waiting period after
the effective days of the employee
coverage or after the date of last rain
statement number c
the employee must survive for 15 days
from the following date of diagnosis of
critical illness the surviving period
must be occur after the waiting period
lastly the the  employee must have
undergone surgery for critical illness
requiring
surgery these benefits indicated above
are subject to the specified gu lines by
sunlight
crepa they still have a question
Ma'am Minor only does that mean it
Uh the condition has to be Uh has to
have all these conditions for what is the
D except for because there is surgery What if
doesn't require surgery it's not him So
ABC only Yes ma'am need to be filled
for the benefit to be released
needed naman all Is there
critical Where is the subject to
only the following requiring surgery is
indicated  the
following conditions that
all have questions still they they Ma'am
Ma'am smiling earlier smiling so
ma'am ha As long as the one earlier with the missis
we won't imitate ma'am ha question is
hers because Yes ma'am What does
B mean 90 days after the
effective date of employees
coverage or
the or after the date of so when enrolling
for example the
employee enrolled Okay He will still wait for 90
days
of critical before
claiming critical illness So what about
C that he needs to survive
days after being diagnosed
the survival period must occur after the
waiting period
Yes 15 days B 105 days Yes I hope
you just put 105 days Why don't you just leave
the 90 and 15 ah usually down to
our clients they are more articulate
they really like that what they hear
especially those those clients who are in the
medical field more what do they have that what is like
Yes okay the D that requires
surgery
Ah but not all critical
illness
if the critical illness It's required
to have the  surgery please
list the critical illness there are
lists because there are ci5 CI 16 CI 32
Okay they still have questions
Ma'am let's give an example just to
illustrate so for example stroke atic
illness is stroke no so it should
occur it should have occurred after 90
days right for for the for the client for
the employee to claim then he still has a
survival period that he lived
for 15 days so another waiting period that
to be total of 105 po
ah Is this a rider or a Rider he is in gyr
okay okay This is ito na yung kaninai
Sinabi namin This is These are the list
of critical illness
covered we call that cib yung kaninai cib
um tadang po nila yung civ cib 5 cib at
saka ib 3c because later we will have a
diagram to illustrate
because we will simplify your
benefits when you become our client So
for cib critical illness five
means five five illness so number
one is acute heart attack number two end
state lung cancer disease number three
n stage renal disease number four
invasive cancer and number five
stroke for cib  critical illness 15 which
is composed of 15 illness number one is
acute heart attack number two Alzheimer
disease number three Vine brain tumor
number four colon artery bypass surgery
number five eales eales
eepal encephalitis number six end stage
liver failure um number seven end stage
lung disease Number eight is end stage
renal disease number nine invasive
cancer number 10 major head trauma
number 11 major organ Transplant
number 12 multiple sclerosis number 13
masculine muscular d dystrophy number
four is parkinson disease number  five
stroke okay for critical illness
36 this one is a bit more so
I won't list them all because there are so
many
Yes Mayon we simplified it We
call the tier one tier two and tier 3
para para po What Yes po
Okay
na lastly is the group hospital benefits
for group hospital cash benefits provide
a fixed cash benefits for every full day
of confinement at least 24
hours up to a maximum of 30 Days so in
the event that the employer gets confined in
the intensive care unit or  icu an
additional benefits equal to  to group
hpit cash benefits will be paid for each
day of confinement up to 30 Days So
they have a question for cash hospital cash
benefits
Ma'am question Okay they got Ong
hospital cash benefit after
hospitalization Yes ma'am so
reimbursement is also
correct Yes ma'am it seems like it's
not like it's like catch benefits
for additional not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's not like it's
reimbursement is correct Yes ma'am it's like it's like it's catch benefits for additional not like it's
he is in
the hospital and
then that's okay
Ma
Yes
oh
um Here are the general exclusions so so
for General exclusion y Uh a number one
is
suicide um not covered during the first
year of the employee coverage for gyr so
that number two is injury due to war
insurrections riot rebellions civil
commotions or hostile actions or of
armed forces number three is murder or
provoke assault
number four is any aviation machine
activities except while the employee is
riding as fair paying passenger in any
marine device  operated by commercial
airlines or ship lines on schedule
passenger trip over establishment
passenger that's why we put him in the
exclusion because Mayon because we call that
passes like example when you have a family
ah with ah with pilot
they give passes except those not paying
so he must be a paying passenger
like for example if we have a family
in the coast guard we are given
passes to R that
particular
ship for free so not that's also excluded they
must also be paying passengers
number five is motor cycling and extreme
sport  example hunting or pillion riding
mountaineering hang  gliding ice or
Winter sport water skiing jumping and
tricks Kayak King beyond 5 km of
Coastal and number six is ​​the free
existing condition fore existing
condition with within first
days from the effective days of UN
employee coverage
soin 3 months bago siya
ma-cover
So sa na
tayo na preexisting con shall mean any
Sickness which
[Music]
existed
either member aware siya or hindi siya
aware ito yun So where the employee have
knowledge or sign or any symptom of
sicknesses where medical advice or
treatment or any laboratory test or
investigation shown that the present of
sickness prior to the effective date of
or statement of the employee benefits
among
others so they have a question about the
exclusion Okay May I have a question down
on pre-existing
condition so does the employee need it
when he enrolls there not What if
when he enrolls he has a pre-existing
condition Yes Okay then something
happened to him after 90
days Okay is that covered Yes ma'am po Yes yes
yes na-satisfied na yung rating
period
so i'm just wondering what will be the
difference down on  contestability is
one
year because that's why I'm being asked.
I have a client who has been
in group life for 90 days or I have a client who
declined because when
they invested they found out that he had a
kidney problem even before the
enrollment but he died more than 6
months into the policy not corporate
so that's why he declined because
they say that the sickness already existed before
he enrolled.
So I'm just clarifying
that if he enrolled with a
pre-existing illness
he can just skip the 90 days and claim is
okay because Ma'am I'm with Sun Life crap
I'm not bragging but based on our
experience we rarely decline Especially
when in group life they decide
because your example is your
medical conditions especially medical
conditions no you've already satisfied
the 90 day waiting period
so I don't see any reason for him to be MCL
if Well for our part that's it I'm not
I'm just speaking for Sun so you're not
you're not strict  when it comes to
pre-existing if you just satisfy
the
Okay let's proceed with next
slide Okay This is the product guidance
this is what I said earlier that um um
we have the tier so tier for tier
number one it should have the head
counts this is the minimum of
five maximum of 90 enrollees or
member nine nine po minimum of five for
tier one minimum of five maximum of n
for plan design uniform coverage only
meaning regardless of their position
Reg manager from down what or five
they are just you know Ma may may dawadah
ranking fight ta's isang manager ta's
isang Alo Okay presidente so it's
uniform Ibigay ng mga lahat from live 100
from tib 50 ganon po dapat lang po
siya So allowed benefits what are the
benefits within that Year One sabi
dito for tier one we have
gyr plus tpd plus Pub plus tib plus
additional the a d
basic na what is for tier number
one So what are the requirements that
we needed for underwriting
still need to be filled out Ah from Five member to nine up
to nine still need to be filled out
member of the health declaration
form Yes, up to 19 from 5 to 19 4
years to that so that he is more like this
4 years to 10 maximum is minimum of 10
maximum of 19 the same is still what their
plan is ah plan design
uniform allowed benefit is the base s Ah
this is it ma'am dyrt Yes and amr
plus ah critical illness benefits the
earlier I said the five critical
illness plus group hospitalization cash
benefits so what is it more concise
when we do it ah
we suggest with clients that Mayon Of course
when um nine is in tier one he is under
tier 1 Not possible is 20
your member we want is tier one because it is cheaper
Not what is it So there are Requirements that are
head
counts
Yes our basic is this you would
notice this one the basic the group life
TP dib fab and tib and a we call it
basic So this basic benefits can be
applied to all so option po yung mga ito
si
cb5 so it is just additional So if
said so we contacted  Leya
for example 20 employees but what she wants is
Basic only she can do it she doesn't have Riders
cib 15 so that's just on top as the number of
employees increases she can
add benefits but always basic
is the universal benefit for
all ah for tier 3 and tier 4 20 minimum
of 20 maximum of 50 here that's okay
ah can be uniform But
she can also be level based if
you want bigger than manager um
assistant manager she can do it but
if you want as just it is uniform it
can also be the same with What's the
only difference between them is ah has
basic Mayon ah for tier number 3 Is cb1
only and then tier number 4 cib 36
is inclusive when what she has
critical illness
included but what is needed n needed
to What fill out the health
declaration
form is there any question it's
easier for us to offer her because
what do we do to
our clients Actually she can do what are the
guidelines when you mute the client
just give them a little idea some of our
clients are aware about those  benefits
Ah but sometimes we also want to give
them each each benefits and
the Rider Then this is what
we will use as a
structure to speed up the
client I have a question The one in the a
Ayung in the a AMR ah usually has 10% to no of the
entire group life insurance but
when you stom it can increase the
AMR coverage Yes ma'am Okay what is the ah
turnaround
date of reimbursements
for us because Ma'am is maximum 15
days upon completion of the
requirements that are working days Ma'am
maximum of 15 working 15 working days
if it exceeds that um you will know
us if it exceeds or follow up
but it is rare
because it usually occurs when the
requirements are exceeded ma'am because ah 'ba ah
ah good thing in sun life group
I'm not sure if
other insurance companies are doing it too we have
different options on the payment or
settlement of the reimbursement First
The traditional is through check This is
really what makes the process take so long
because there is still check preparation
processing because second is Ada  or
we call it kine na lang sa bank
account ng member so once he is approved na
siya ang kahagan din po sa Sun Life
wea Is that we accept soft copy of the
reimbursement documents and then when
we receive soft C Of course ppr
pprc na siya ng claims Department na ng
approve namin si client o
padala niyo na yung hard copy kasi na
siya ng approve So because of course we
still require hard copy kasi for audit
purposes we That's what I reiterated we
require the hard copy and then when
that is Po Pilipi namin si member What do
they want to either check
or accredit na siya na siya sa bank account ng
member so the process is faster
Because when he is credited to the
members bank n-no ify din namin si HR na kaniya na kin na ng bank account na ng
member para ma-check na rin okay
for some because they require the original
documents pag claim lang Pero pag amr
hindi mm Yes reimbursement Because this is a hospital right
Yes so mga mga extens So all
that you need original Yes ma'am
everything before you release
payment correct
Okay what's up  OK, no, it's just a minor
question, for example, are
tiers 3 and 4 higher, more
critical illnesses are covered? What if,
for example, they want a company
that is in tier 3 or 4 but only five
critical illnesses covered could be
pede, there's still a
question, okay.
100,000 for T pdi 100,000 and then for
family assistant or fab is
10,000 tib is 50,000 accident dead and
dismember or the a d is
100,000 so the ann  ual premium for
employee is
342 or tier number one
that So this is the cheapest most basic
but basic what it is So It's easier
what it is It's easier
[Music]
Whatever it is
Yes but the
300 next slide
or for tier number two if
you want something higher for tier number two it's the
tier the question is Ma'am
when the employee is only minimum
of 5 to 9 unfortunately that's all that will be
offered when based on the number of
heads so that's
our requirements but as that's as the employee
increases
His options for the benefits or the coverage are also increasing so
This is it when with 10 to 19 employees it
can also be below 200 it can be
100 or 200 so the minimum is always
100,000 342 that's why we say this is the
best seller because php32 in a year for a
100,000 coverage He already has life
He already has an accident so This is it
for 200,000 It's okay on the next
slide It's Mayon the premium because you can
remove the critical illness
and gcb ' can it be only 200,000
it also has a certain premium for the
coverage sig
next so These are the options if 200,000 It
will be 684 per head per year
that's the basic unlike 100,000 which is
342 this is 684 for 200,000 so these are the
options or
variations we just send you a copy because
I'm sure We
can't even memorize all that
so it's
really a paper or Of course any document
AER Yes that's why it's
always better to say we're a franchise and then we
will give you a formal proposal that
will be your guide for Of course when we
offer and present to the member to the
client Those are the premiums
benefits
so
Ah this one is for tier number 3 from 20
to 50 employees That's what
[Music]
Like for example what ni wants
at level 3 po
300 notice po ba y is always 10% of the
basic life po po y the question is
how much is the coverage again this is box
type prototype po siya package so
naka-fix na po But if you want Or the
client prefers a higher benefit or
higher coverage maximum of 20% yung
ating mof for
theb and even The Accidental medical
reimbursement It's always 10% that's the
standard but we can go as High as 20%
Okay on the next slide na po
o na po yung mga ano premium yung
kanina yung mga coverage and then This
is the
premium may commercial
Mas madali Ong ibenta
maam Yes tsaka hindi siya siya very much What po
Yes po office Base po po kasi there are
companies kasi na ssep nila yung health
insurance nila with their life may mga
ganon kasing mga incidents Like for
example yung nyoniyo meron sila ah
insured sila yung health insurance nila
from different companies and then they
want to have the live insurance with sun
grepa you can offer this one kapag ano po
Okay na po next po
for tier number f na rin po yung m
coverage nila from level 12 to
5 then we're going to discuss about
what are his prices, his premium,
just to take note of this. There is this
benefit group hospital cash
benefit. This is what Lea discussed earlier,
per day like the ICU or ordinary
room. She has a per day of 1.
It also depends on whether
our confinement is comprehensive or due to accident, it's
cheaper when it's an accident
only. Okay, next slide,
or the premium.
Okay, let's proceed with another
slide.
How do these benefits
work?
Oh, by the way. These files have been
provided to Albert or James. It will
be shared in your shared folder.
Okay, Ma'am, these are
our illustrations. It seems like you
asked earlier how the benefit
works. When will there be a claim?
We will
be discussing our health
care. Maybe you'll have more questions.
This is just for group life prote.
Again, this is for the MSMEs,
micro small medium enterprises, small
groups, minimum of five up to 200,
so again, this is for the protection,
no.  We are still in health care so
let's do it
hipster But that's okay It's very
interested very This is the health
insurance plan for small enterprises
That's why we call it hipster This is
the comparable to I can't
say HMO but on the traditional or
the medical reimbursement type This is
because the difference is next slide
I didn't discuss the company because
Lea has already discussed it Okay okay Sorry okay
so again hipster because give the
best of both Worlds We are the same in
customized this one is package that has
readymade premium readymade
benefits the members can have access
either cashless because we will be
providing the medical card dental card
so Once they go to any of our accredited
hospitals and clinics they will just
present the card and then passport that
they will end they will assist them
until they are given treatment
or if the member goes to their preferred
doctor hospital or clinic they pay first
and file for reimbursement
Is the reimbursement full
reimbursement? Of course, what are
we going to base it on?  he's on the benefits
of the member but of course it's always be
100% based on the benefits yes ma'am
because it's only 80% is the maximum
30,000 we're 100% based on the inner
limits because we have a table and
then again this is package with life
disability and accident I didn't
explain his life because
Lea already discussed him what I'm going to discuss
is more in the medical side or the
healthcare
side okay so we have not
more than
1,400 buses we've been Increasing the
numbers It's more than 1,600
nationwide ah that's our hospitals and
clinics partners or accredited same with
the doctors ongoing po yyung our
accreditation and
affiliation and then we have this 24x 7
cutline and then We also have the
teleconsult that the member can
use Again the members or the eligible
would be minimum of 5  to 200 of course for
regular full time well  It still depends
on the company if they would offer it to
their probationary employees but mostly
It's being given to the regular
employees full time 18 to 64 years old
termination upon attainment of age
65 and then that's also Workforce should be
85% non hazardous mostly office based so
the common ones are the
msmes like even hardware or
small companies even parlors or
salons this is our
market the product design so again It's
a comb It's a both protection and health
care on the protection side This is your
life insurance 24x7 covered member
on and off the
job 365 Days in a year same as the
health care in health care so
we will be focusing more on the health
care when we say basic benefit This is the
inti or the confinement out patient this is the
This is the commonly used
consultation laboratory that
the member is not confined Again the
difference of inpatient
confined out patient This is the
commonly used because of course like may ubo
may Fever not us  immediately
confine consult first laboratory
protection so I didn't call
protection he has already discussed it thoroughly
So what are the benefits this is more
on the health care so when we say
impatient Is this what we say
impatient member is confined within 24
at least 24 hours Why 24 hours This is
part of the requirement of heal because
not all confinement is given fail
health benefit we know that
fail health is now also case rated there are still
3 days like that
so that we cannot control that is part
of the pH health
guidelines so These are the benefits
under confinement of course there is room and
board this is the room that the
member goes to either room peso value or room
category hospital services these are the
miscellaneous These are the medicines
laboratory tests that the
doctor requires for the treatment of the patient
surgical benefit if ever the
member has an operation Surgeon that
we will pay for the Surgeon Of course when there is an
operation there is an anesthesiologist
there is anesthesia
physician and specialist Fe he is now part
of  confinement of course you have a doctor
attending physician ambulance fee If
there is a Need For you to be
transferred from one hospital to another
again We also cover emergency cases but
Later we will be discussing What are the
emergencies in nature What is it before
we identify him to be an
emergency case for out patient
these are the ones that no longer
require confinement
again consultation and basic diagnostic
procedures why am I reiterating the
basic because Mayon for our program We
only cover the basic because there are
HMOs so there might be a miss interpretation because
they have what we call comprehensive
diagnostic procedures This is the most
laboratory test they even
have therapeutic so for us for
hipster We only cover basic
diagnostic so This is the one We also be
adding or it's an option that we cover
annual physical exam because
we know even the small companies they
part of the DOLE ' every year before
they renew their licenses they
need to have an x-ray
their members are physically fit so instead of paying
them an additional physical exam we
incorporate it to their program So it
includes physical exam urinalysis
fecalysis x-ray and blc
Pre-employment is not included
but again reimbursed
Annual physical exam cannot be booked because we
arrange it to any of our ACC clinics
either walk in or onsite when onsite
we only have a minimum
requirement of 50 at least or 100
questions regarding ape What is that 2
weeks prior to the date or Do you have a
turnaround time when
the annual checkup will be advised Yes as much as
possible we would be asking requiring
an ample time for us to coordinate
with the clinic for the animal physical exam especially
if walk in but for example the
client's preferred date is March 1 so
we will be notified at least 2 weeks
before then we
will make a decision
clinic by batch within one month so
one month is enough time for
them to do their annual physical exam for
walk in But if we still need to
extend then let us know so
we can extend it to the provider Okay so in terms of
the providers everything is ok  of
your accredited clinics are
also accredited for
AV Yes but we Of course when the client We
will only designate a certain clinic
they cannot go is one
healthway one for patients first one for
hypertension
they should be common Maybe uniform for all
all employees must go to one designated
clinic only Okay thank you thank
you I have a question there Yes how do
I separate the office Yes that is
happening right That's right That's right
There is a head office there is one in the
provincial like Sir Albert's example
earlier ' is that possible but what about
the Nest there in the area Like for
example in the province there is no high
precision there is no port Med there are no
patients first what is the
clinic near there in the area of
that provincial branch We will
coordinate okay I have
clients who work from home all So how is
that HR will cover
them so usually based on Residence
if that's the case when that's
only within Metro Manila No ah
nationwide too So if that's the case Ma'am the
best for me is the one I saw the
most branches because it is
hypertension so we will check what is
really the closest to them so
they can go there for ape  if there is still no
high precision in the area,
we will definitely tell you what the
clinic is like down there because we also have
such clients that are spread out among the
members.
Okay, another question. Okay, Ma'am, are you sure the
ape is part of the utilization or not for
us, Ma'am, it's not
outsourced because it's a fixed expense.
Okay
[Music]
thanks, so in computing, it's
being removed immediately.
Okay then. We also have dental. This is
again an additional benefit. The
employer can opt not to get this dental benefit
for their employees but we have
this partnered with health partners. No
reimbursement. Then it is allowed. These
are the benefits
covered. What are the basic twice a
year prophylaxis, simple to extract.
Adjustments of Ventures.
So it again. These are the
exclusions that were just added here.
Again, he doesn't have access to major
hospitals because he's a
hipster. His benefit is small. His
premium is small when
he goes to St. LS BGC or QC. He
maxes out
his benefit immediately. So he'll shout too, but
only these five.  St Luke's
BGC St Luke's QC Makati Med the Medical
City pasic and Asian Hospital the rest
they have
access as long as ACC Creed the
hospital is Sun Life grepa to
that hospital or if not yet file for
reimbursement So there is also a 90 day waiting
period for the pre-existing
functional psychiatric disorders
but not limited to anxiety or
depression circumcision immunizations
That is not covered acupuncture
chiropractic reflexes because it's not
yet accepted by
medical treatment Uh  expenses incurred
due to pregnancy also because it is
said that giving birth is not a pain so these are
our tiers we have delux and
premier so again 5 to
20 we have to
each employee to fill out health
declaration form when more than 21 21
and Above no declaration or no forms
needed and then they have the
option either uniform or parareho po
they share the benefits or by
level maximum of two levels only when
delux or maximum of three when
premier but  only be one one plan higher
Can't be bigger  The gap
and then for some because like We have some
cases that are independent Why do we still put
in independent aff because the others are
exp or non fail health member but
the standard is on top of fail health
we are sorry we are not here on top
of f
health The independent Because they very rarely
take employees Because all
employees are not
fail health members
these are the benefits now the coverage
we have five options from plan
50 easy to remember plan 50 plan 75 100
125 and 150 it follows with the benefit
Maam Sorry regarding heal magkan single
fors independent heal premium separate
prum I'll show
so It just follows nga 50 75 100 150
this is for the grp insurance or the
protection and then this ito na po yung
health care benefits itself so again 575
750 1,150 and 155 we're different from
HMO because this as you would notice the
rin board is based on the pes of value
or the it doesn't Uh followed the
room category  like small private award
regular private sweet like that so for
us ah peso value room rate room
rates So you would also notice that it
has inner limits unlike HMO it's just room and
board and then mbl so
you'll notice later that
his premium is also low So when we say as charge as
long as he doesn't get the maximum donon
or get excited
the 15,000 based on the ruv we have what we
call rel unit value depending on
the complexity of the operation it
varies from 5% up to
100% and again It's always 50% he is the
anesthesiologist of
surgical So for example the
surgical is only 10,000 50% of 10,000
only maximum again these are all maximum
so it's also 31 days per confinement
because sell the like earlier ' did
you ask for icu or regular room 30 Days
because it's rarely an isolated case that the
member is confined for more than 30 days so 50,000 again this is per
illness per year This  The premium
is outpatient so also We have a
separate inpatient and outpatient
benefit for out patient 12,000 maximum
per year annual benefit limit he
can't
relax
400 the re-karma-men
[Music]
mri mri maybe a bone marrow transplant Ma'am
unfortunately mri is not covered in
Basic Yes it's not yet comprehensive because
we say basic it's just blood C
Xray Yes as in Basic it's really just but
again no this is
V it's okay
but we're not that
eager you're
not that eager because just yesterday someone
asked me m But
in
Bacolod Bacolod the area then
another concern there ma'am the
amla the antim laundering the
cows their requirements M
and so as a group as in the group government
What is it how amla the ones who
will pay because
their findings are government or company employees do they
have a share like that okay because
there's a rule now that the 7
7,000 issh  government employee The government will answer,
okay 7,000 per
person is pretty good sometimes it's in the
budget, no Yes, that's why I remembered because there's
7,000 down there, but or 6,000 Sorry So
what's up Okay if it's not possible here if
he customizes it, that's possible Next
question As long as ma'am He's not bidding Does
he not have Bing I don't know yet
but but if no one
else is offering or or do you think there's only one
opponent there ' is it worth entering
that correct if Of course Ma'am you said it's
Bacol We have to check first the
accredited hospitals in the area, ma'am It's
good that we have identified the
area so we cannot enter into a
battle that we don't know what
we are entering so we can further this
So okay that's what I'll tell the ag
we can explore We can try Okay good
thank you there no harm in trying Ma'am
more more on that po What if Government
employees they enter
their cooperative or when the coop also has one
requirement
amla who funded whom in the
cooperative's budget fund budget
Yeah they will pay the cooperative
Yes but there is still that document I know it is
requested because it is not possible
ma'am Yes it is possible it is possible
because the others we offered to those who
got it As long as the ones like the
Associations of tricycles like that
drivers Yeah toal you don't have kyc
employee level 'ba So it is customized now It will
not be included in the package
yeah the important thing is it is included in
bbm's 7,000 budget Okay thank
you Yes ma'am let's talk about that so
these are the only benefits Oh sorry
this is without group health care on top of
F
health So it means all
members or employees are fel health
members This is it Oh sorry ma'am This is
independent but this is rarely
this is when they have group health care
but this is also rarely Ma'am the first one Ma'am
is without virgin account It means this is what
we usually offer 68
6787 plan 50 on top of PH health virgin
account
next Ma this is it  Mayon,
who is the current benefit or current
provider on top of F health,
just increased his benefit by almost
Php500. This is
annual how these benefits work. So during
confinement, we have what is called a
restoration of benefits. There is a restoration
period for
7 days or whatever. There are less than
45 days remaining. The
only benefit we can give is his balance.
But when he has been for more than 45 days,
the benefit of the same illness will be restored to 100%.
But when
he has a different illness, another set of
benefits.
Sorry, Ma'am, sorry, sorry,
he just sampled the limit
so the fourth confinement was covered in full.
2,400 because he is still in school. So
his remaining balance is only
150 out of 2,400, so
his benefit for the second confinement is only 129,000.
His limit has not been restored. We just shared this so
you can put it in the shared folder. Yes,
ma'am, you can still deduct
the Fil health part from it. Yes, it is always Fil
health first before.
What is this? It has been restored?  that he is
more than 45 days from second to
third even  that's
NC Yes ma'am as long as
he recovered in the 45 days from
the time he left the
hospital Yes ma'am for the same
illness this one is for the
availment process because we have an
emergency in patient and outpatient
when an emergency layman's term should be a
matter of life and death like an
accident dehydration or
high fever high BP
he can go straight to the emergency
room to be treated as an
emergency case to go to any of our
emergency room the the er personel will
treat the patient present the card or
if there is no card any valid ID
just to identify the employee Sun Life
crepa member
the card but if For example, there is
no card Si member called
that on the hotline and then upon discharge
Check the documents and settle any
uncovered charges if for
admission he will go to the
admission or impatient procedure again
when there is for admission you admitting
Order and then present the valid ID or
the sun crepa medical
card and then issp po siya kapag wala nga pong
card or naiwan or na Nawala
Just call the ER of the
hospital staff at the Sun Life grapa hotline
or if ever I can't contact you I'll
be honest because like before
I assisted someone the approval time is still assisting it
happens I can't tell you what to do
What is the perfect system it
happens because there is of course
queuing and then what we will do please
inform us We will endorse or we
will call the hotline the hotline will
call the member Pao to give the
approval
code Especially when the hours are 11 to 2
These are the discharge hours at the
hospitals so they are very busy pick
hours that are called then We also have
a licon officer that monitors the
adition and issues loa and then of course
We will remind the member to F to file
their f help because
Albert said PH help first before Sun Life
prepa Just like any other HMO
for our patient consultation We have some we do
n't have Sun Life repa
clinics like the others that we see
medical medicard or maxicare do
they have clinics within the  Metro
Manela we are only clinics of
our accredited ones but we have one at
RCBC Plaza in Makati grepa life medical
but of course that is far away if it is not
accessible to the member any of our
accredited clinics will do present the the
the card issp po rin siya then that po iti-siya na si member po rin po tayo as we discussed before Pwede rin tayo mag-is
faster
by email directly, let's say,
we will assist the member,
I will email Maria Ana, so it's faster
on messenger, it's still better to
email us or text. So what is faster,
email or email? Okay, because on
Facebook Messenger, maybe I can't bot
it, okay, or I cannot guarantee
that there will be someone assigned to
Don, who is always monitoring FB.
Okay, unlike us, just office hours
or text, even after office hours, text or
call. We are easy. Okay,
than. He doesn't want teleconsultation.
So we also have. Of course,
this is to give weight to
our trending times. Like what happened during the
pandemic, there were teleconsultation
services. We still have. We still have
this service, but mostly now
we noticed that teleconsultations are no longer available. Of course, it's
good. Face-to-face
reimbursement. This is what happened
with teleconsultation. Let's just look again.
He has scheduled it. Yes, the one who calls will schedule it.
Then the Doctor will call you.
Viber or online. So the doctor will
call the member directly.  There is no
schedule. Give him a schedule. There is a
link that will
be given. Actually, there are clients
who prefer teleconsultation
rather than going to a real consult,
especially to save
time. At least we have
other services like teleconsultation,
whichever they
prefer. This is what we do when we scan it
first. We will be giving the email
address and then a hard copy to
Sun
Life. These are the ones with less
requirements for reimbursement.
The cleaning forms will probably be sent
to the client or
HR. Of course, we can send a
soft copy because normally what
we give is a PDF file. It seems to be
editable. Now it seems to be a soft
copy.
Ma'am, sorry, I don't know what the soft
copy is. The clean form is complete. When it is
complete, um, then we will give
the hard copy. The original copy is first.
Give us the soft copy
scan immediately. We will evaluate our conditions
once approved. We will
send the hard copy. That's the
time that we will settle. Okay, it is more
efficient than the hard copy that was sent. It's not enough. Because
when
The documents are not enough, they go
back and forth again when scanned, it is immediately apparent that something is
missing.
What is the physical exam? It will take at
least 7 working days to
notify us of the preferred
hospital or clinic, but preferably a clinic,
prefer date and
then that. So for the dental, always make
an appointment to any of our
accredited ones, the trunk line number is
last,
so we encourage you to share like or
follow our Sun Life Crepa Healthcare
Facebook page so you would be informed
for any developments or
information.